准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
胆小鬼
海绵宝宝
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
客串音乐嘉宾
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
海底的万圣节跟地面没有区别
Halloween is no different under the waves--
海盗  骷髅
Pirates, skeletons
还有海怪
and sea monsters
抱歉
Sorry
所有人玩得都很开心
Everyone having fun
蟹堡王
万圣节快乐
几乎所有人
Well, almost everyone
谁在那
Who's there?
嘣
蟹老板  盘子都洗完了
Okay, Mr. Krabs, the dishes are done--
我要走了
I'm leaving
等一下
Hold on
不想听我一年一篇的鬼故事吗
Don't you want to hear my annual scary story?
不用了谢谢  蟹老板
No, thank you, Mr. Krabs
故事里是不是有怪物
Does it have monsters in it?
是
Aye--
最最凶残的怪物
The worst monster of them all
不听
No
是真实发生的吗
Is it a true story?
跟大海一样真
True as the deep blue
好吧  那我还是听一听吧
Okay, maybe just a little
请坐下  我的小子
Have a seat, me boy
烫
Hot
每年  在万圣节前夕
Every year, on Halloween night
飞天魔鬼会驾着海盗船降临裤头村
the Flying Dutchman
descends on Bikini Bottom in a pirate ship
差不多像这样  但是大一些
just like this, only bigger
请问一下
Excuse me
他的船样子是不是像蟹黄堡
Did his ship look like a Krabby Patty?
正如我所说
Like I was saying
飞天魔鬼会突然俯冲下来
the Flying Dutchman swoops down
开始偷取人们的灵魂
and starts stealing people's souls
灵魂的样子是不是很像腌椰菜
Do souls look like pickles?
是  其实确实如此
Aye, as a matter of fact, they do
然后他会放到你绝对取不到的地方
Then he puts them
where you can never get them--
灵魂袋里
in his soul bag
灵魂
蟹堡王
我是来取你腌椰菜的
I've come for your pickle
胆小鬼海绵宝宝一年比一年好吓
Scaredy-Pants gets easier to scare every year
章鱼哥
Squidward
精彩的鬼故事效果就是好  对吧小子
Nothing like a good ghost story, eh, me boy?
希望你今晚来我这的派对可别被吓到
Hope you're not too scared to come to me party tonight
胆小鬼海绵宝宝
SpongeBob Scaredy-Pants
偷走你的灵魂
Steal your soul
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat
没事的  儿子
It's okay, son
那只是胆小鬼海绵宝宝而已
That's just SpongeBob Scaredy-Pants
万圣节快乐  胆小鬼海绵宝宝
Happy Halloween, Scaredy-Pants
我叫海绵宝宝
The name's SquarePants
是海绵宝宝
It's SquarePants
我不明白  小蜗
I don't get it, Gary
每年万圣节  不管我尽了多大的力
Every Halloween, no matter how hard I try
大家还是会吓到我
everybody scares me
我已经烦透了
Well, I'm sick of it
绝不再当胆小鬼海绵宝宝
No more Scaredy-Pants
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
小蜗  派大星来了
Gary, it's Patrick
我要去吓吓他
I'm going to scare him
轮到我了
It's my turn
你好啊  海绵宝宝
Hiya, SpongeBob
抱歉  我不是有意要吓到你的
Sorry, I didn't mean to scare you
为什么我一次都吓不到别人
Why can't I be frightening for once?
我的机会在哪
Where's my chance?
如果你想要吓人的话
If you want to be scary
就要有套好的打扮
you're going to need a good costume
我打扮咋样
What do you think?
太好了
Great
当我的糖果袋刚刚好
You're going as my trick-or-treat bag
不对
No, no
我是飞天魔鬼的幽灵
I'm the ghost of the Flying Dutchman
少了点什么
Something's missing
有了
I know
快穿上吧  飞天魔鬼
Step into these babies, Hans
太可怕了
Terrifying
感觉不行  派大星
I don't know, Patrick
快啊  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
有小孩子来了
It's little kids
小孩子可好吓了
Little kids are easy to scare
不给糖就捣蛋
Trick or treat
快看  是闹鬼的床垫
Look, it's the haunted mattress
好了好了
Okay, okay--
糖果拿去
Here's your candy
不用了
No, please
这样就够了
That was enough of a treat
谢谢
Thank you
我不明白  派大星
I don't get it, Patrick
海绵宝宝  来看看我新做的纸幽灵
SpongeBob, look at my new paper ghost
好可怕
Scary
就是这个  派大星
That is it, Patrick
怎么了
What's it?
我跟那个幽灵有什么地方不一样
What's the difference between that ghost and me?
不不不  等一下
No, no, no, wait
先别说
Don't tell me
我能答出来的
I can do this
先别说答案
Don't tell me
好吧  你说
Okay, tell me
我脑袋是方的
I've got a square head
真正幽灵的脑袋是圆的
and a real ghost has a round one
只要让我的脑袋变圆  然后
All we have to do is make my head round and--
我就变可怕了
I'm scary
好  准备好了吗
Okay, are you ready?
记住  要弄成这样
Remember, like this
你真的确定想这样吗
You sure you want to do this?
刮我脑袋  让我变圆起来
Shave me down, make me round
好了
All right
开始刮吧
Let's get to it
我打扮咋样
What do you think?
完美
Perfect
这样才叫吓人
Now, that's scary
一块去吓个人吧
Let's go scare somebody
我是飞天魔鬼
I'm the Flying Dutchman
我不知道我是谁
I don't know who I am
我是飞天魔鬼
I'm the Flying Dutchman
我是飞天魔鬼最好的朋友
I'm the Flying Dutchman's best friend
你们小朋友不要糖了吗
Don't you kids want your candy?
天啊  刚才真是好家伙
Oh, boy, that was something
你的打扮真的好有效
Your costume really packs a punch
真这么觉得吗
Do you think?
那是当然的了
No question
你把那家伙狠狠地吓着了
You scared the barnacles off that guy
我们接下来该吓谁
Who should we scare next?
蟹堡王办了个派对  里面全都是人
There's a whole party just full of people
down at the Krusty Krab
飞天魔鬼要不请自来
and the Flying Dutchman is going to show up uninvited
现在就有人来了
Here comes someone now
我是飞天魔鬼
I'm the Flying Dutchman
这不是刚才那个闹鬼床垫吗
Wasn't that the haunted mattress?
他估计是被贬成闹鬼睡袋了
I guess he's been demoted to a haunted sleeping bag
蟹堡王
万圣节快乐
爸  你又害得我好尴尬
Oh, dad, you're embarrassing me again
你好啊  章鱼哥
Howdy, Squidward
我是说飞天魔鬼
I mean Flying Dutchman
派对是不是很棒
Great party, huh?
你打扮的是什么
What are you supposed to be?
我是养在鱼缸里的宠物小金鱼
Why, I'm a pet goldfish in a bowl
我看不懂
I don't get it
准备好了吗  海绵宝宝
Are you ready, SpongeBob?
好了  派大星
Okay, Patrick
关灯
Kill the lights
我是飞天魔鬼
I am the Flying Dutchman
把你们的灵魂给我
Give me your souls
那不是飞天魔鬼
That's no Dutchman
是海绵宝宝
That's SpongeBob
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
SpongeBob
救命
Help
我不是海绵宝宝
I am not SpongeBob
那是我的便服
Those are my street clothes
飞天魔鬼
Flying Dutchman?
得叫飞天笨蛋
Flying Dopeman
够了
Enough
是真的飞天魔鬼
It's the real Flying Dutchman
你们胆小鬼看得没错
You bet your lily white livers
我就是飞天魔鬼
I'm the Flying Dutchman
给你们透露个小秘密
And I'll let you in on a little secret
我要偷取你们的灵魂
I'm going to steal your soul
安静
Quiet
都是你们自找的  大个爱哭鬼
You had it coming, you big crybabies
每年人们都会打扮成我的样子
Every year, people dressing like me
把飞天魔鬼的名号变成了笑话
Turning the Flying Dutchman name
into a laughingstock
但我要取走你们灵魂  并非因为那个
But that's not the reason I'm taking your souls
而是这个成为了压垮骆驼的最后稻草
No, this is the straw that broke the camel's back
在我见过的所有飞天魔鬼打扮当中
Out of all the Dutchman costumes I've seen
就属你的最冒犯我
yours is the most insulting
你意思是不是我不吓人
Do you mean I'm not scary?
就你
You?
还吓人
Scary?
让我告诉你什么叫吓人  小朋友
Let me tell you about scary, kid
世界上有各种各样吓人的东西
There's all kinds of scary things in the world
蜘蛛很吓人
Spiders are scary
我很吓人
I'm scary
你呢
You?
你不吓人
You're not scary
好  来把事情成了吧
Okay, let's get this over with
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
首先我要把你这套破打扮摘掉
First I got to get rid of this stupid costume
可真想不到
What do you know
我吓到他了
I scared him
成功了  派大星
It worked, Patrick
我吓到大家了
I scared everybody
是啊
Yeah
估计是因为你的粉红色帽子
I guess it was your pink hat
粉红色帽子
Pink hat?
那不是帽子
That's not a hat
是我的大脑
That's my brain
别担心
Don't worry
会长回来的
It grows back
我是少年蜗
分镜总监
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜
编剧
动画总监
创意总监
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
锻炼时间结束了  小蜗
Exercise time is over, Gary
可不能让你变太瘦了
We don't want you getting too thin
来  小蜗
Here, boy
捡回来
Fetch
干得漂亮  小蜗
Good job, Gary
我爱你  小蜗
I love you, Gary
小蜗
Gary
快下去  小蜗
Down, boy
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
准备好了吗
Are you ready?
准备什么
For what?
捉水母年度大会
The annual jellyfish convention
这周末要在尤克里里村举办
in Ukulele bottom this weekend
那你准备好了吗
So you ready or what?
这周末就要办吗
That was this weekend?
我去不了
I can't go
没人帮我照顾小蜗
I don't have anyone to take care of Gary
能不能别再把你内衣
Would you please stop leaving your undergarments
放我庭院里了
on my front lawn?
章鱼哥  你这周末能帮忙看下小蜗吗
Squidward, could you watch Gary this weekend?
什么是只小蜗
What's a Gary?
不是只小蜗
Not a Gary--
要叫小蜗
Gary
是我的宠物蜗牛
He's my pet snail
说你好
Say "Hello"
你养的居然是这么个东西
You actually care for that thing?
我爱小蜗
I love Gary
我可不帮你
Well, I don't
找别人去吧
Get somebody else
看来咱们周末没法走了  派大星
I guess we can't go away this weekend after all, Patrick
走了
Go away?
你是说  要是我照看小蜗的话
You mean, if I watch Gary
你们一整个周末都要走
you guys will be gone all weekend?
其实咱这个周末有三天时间
Actually, a three-day weekend
也就是三天都不在了
As in "Not here for three days"?
对  不过你说过你不帮我的
Yeah, but you've already said you can't do it
我们能理解
We understand
不要难过  章鱼哥
Don't feel bad, Squidward
我们三个还是能
The three of us can still have
在你家里自个儿办捉水母大会
our own jellyfish convention at your house
我改主意了
I changed my mind
你们周末应该走
You guys deserve a weekend away
你会帮忙吗
You'll do it?
太好了
Great
我来给你教一下照顾蜗牛的事项
Let me show you a little bit about snail care
你一天要遛两次小蜗
You need to take Gary for a walk twice a day
周五周六还有周天
Friday, Saturday and Sunday--
三天的周末
a three-day weekend
教你要怎么喂小蜗
Let me show you how to feed him
小蜗
我把所有罐子都做了标记
I have all the cans marked
早
晚
早上一罐  晚上一罐
A can in the morning and a can at night
这样就够了吗
Sure it's enough?
捉水母
Jellyfishing
车来了
The bus is here
快点  海绵宝宝
Come on, SpongeBob
捉水母
Jellyfishing
好了  该走了
Well, time to go
可别迟到
Don't want to be late
拜拜
Bye-bye
我的指示你应该不会忘记吧
Now you won't forget my instructions, will you?
我记性好得不得了
I have the memory of an elephant
我会照顾好小弗的
I'll take good care of Fred
小蜗
Gary
好  才怪呢
Right, yeah, right
捉水母
Jellyfishing
再见了  大废物
So long, losers
他们走了
They're gone
这三天会是我一生中最美好的三天
This is going to be the best three days of my life
我要做完所有
I'm going to do all the things
海绵宝宝害我没法正常做的事
I can't normally do because of SpongeBob
三天后
捉水母
Jellyfishing
好了
Well
我一生中最美好的周末就这样结束了
thus ends the greatest weekend of my life
没有海绵宝宝  没有派大星
No SpongeBob, no Patrick
就只有我我我
nothing but me, me, me
捉水母
Jellyfishing
蜗牛
The snail
忘记蜗牛了
I forgot the snail
必须做点什么
I've got to do something
小蜗
好了好了好了
Okay, okay, okay
来来来  就在这
Here we go, here we go, right here
吃
Eat
你必须把饭都吃完
You've got to finish this food
再见  派大星
See you later, Patrick
快吃啊
Come on, eat
吃
Eat
小蜗  我回来了
Gary, I'm home
嗨  海绵宝宝
Hi, SpongeBob
章鱼哥  你在这干什么
Squidward, what are you doing here?
只是在
Just, uh
帮你检查一下小蜗
checking up on old Gary for you
你可真是个好朋友  章鱼哥
What a great friend you are, Squidward
那
So
我们等会再见
Well, I guess I'll see you later
拜
Bye
谢了  章鱼哥
Thanks, Squidward
你就是能靠得住
I can always count on you
小蜗
Gary
小蜗  你怎么了
Gary, what's happened to you?
哪里有问题
What's wrong?
章鱼哥  小蜗出事了
Squidward, something's wrong with Gary
章鱼哥
Squidward
对对  就跟我想的一样
Yes, yes, it's just as I thought
怎么了
What?
这绝对是蜗牛
This is definitely a snail
我就知道
I knew it
章鱼哥  你听到了吗
Oh, Squid, did you hear that?
所以  蜗牛血浆
Therefore, a shot of snail plasma
必须要小心注射
must be carefully administered
拿去
Here you go
你要来注射吗
You're gonna do it?
不行
No
我晕针
I'm too squeamish
等一下  医生
Hang on, doc
我来帮你提包
Let me help you with your bag there
章鱼哥  等等
Squid, wait
我没法帮小蜗注射血浆
I can't give Gary his plasma
我也晕针
I'm squeamish, too
海绵宝宝  我可不想
SpongeBob, I don't want to
小蜗
Gary
好好好  我来注射
Okay, okay, I'll do it
可别伤着人家了  章鱼哥
Now, don't hurt him, Squidward
好  稳一点
Okay, steady
等等  太用力了
Wait, that's too hard
好
Okay
再来一次
Try it again
等等
Wait
抱着别动
Hold him still
等等
Wait
你抱着别动
You hold him still
等等
Wait
章鱼哥
Squidward
你把蜗牛血浆注射到我身上了
you've injected me with snail plasma
都是你逼我的
Well, you made me do it
我会怎么样
What's gonna happen to me?
根本没什么  一点蜗牛血浆而已
Nothing, it's just a little snail plasma
不好说  我感觉不对劲
I don't know, I feel kind of funny
都是因为你想太多了
I'm telling you it's all in your head
水
这玩意只是要水
He just needed water?
小蜗  你好多了
Oh, Gary, you're better
太感人了
How touching
我要回家去吐一阵子
I'm going to go home and throw up
晚安
Good night
章鱼哥别走
Squidward, wait
蜗牛血浆
The snail plasma
相信我  海绵宝宝
Trust me, SpongeBob
你不会有事的
Nothing's going to happen to you
你好得很
You're fine
你放心  小蜗
Don't worry, Gary
章鱼哥说我会没事的
Squidward says I'll be fine
他无所不知
He knows everything
那你饿了吗
So, you hungry?
小蜗
拿去
Here you go
吃吧  小蜗
Eat up, Gary
抱歉小蜗  我控制不住自己
Sorry, Gary, I couldn't control myself
我怎么会那样
Why'd I just do that?
我要垮掉了吗
Am I cracking up?
不对
No
不对  章鱼哥说得对
No, Squidward's right
我没事
I'm fine
是我多虑了
I worry too much
我想太多了
It's all in my head
我感觉好极了
I feel tip-top
小蜗  你速度变快了
Gary, you're getting a lot faster
看看我
Look at me
好得不能再好了
Never better
我没事
I'm okay
章鱼哥说我好得很
Squidward said I'm fine
小蜗
Gary
我好得很
I'm fine
看吧
You see?
没事
That's okay
反正我是左撇子
I'm a lefty, anyway
现在我用不着买新鞋子了
Now I don't have to buy those new shoes
我把话收回去  小蜗
I take it back, Gary
我就是出问题了
Something is wrong with me
希望以后再也看不到蜗牛了
I hope I never see another snail again
晚安  竖笛
Good night, Clari
会是谁来了
Who could that be?
搞得跟我不知道似的
As if I didn't already know
海绵宝宝  我都跟你说了
SpongeBob, I already told you
你会没事
you're going to be just fi--
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
海神王啊  我都干了些什么
Oh, Neptune, what have I done?
全都是你的错
It's all your fault
好
Okay
集中精神  章鱼哥
Get it together, Squidward
要是我喂了蜗牛  这一切都不会发生
None of this would be happening
if I'd only fed that snail
你们能不能安静点
Will you clam up?
好了小鬼们  准备好了吗
All right, boils and ghouls, you ready?
好了
Yeah
那么
Well
是谁住在深海的坟场附近
Who lives near a graveyard under the sea?
胆小鬼海绵宝宝
SpongeBob Scaredy-Pants
方方黄黄  吓人自如
Absorbent and yellow and spooky is he
胆小鬼海绵宝宝
SpongeBob Scaredy-Pants
如果四处受怕是你的愿望
If nautical chills be something you wish
胆小鬼海绵宝宝
SpongeBob Scaredy-Pants
那就大声尖叫像大鱼弹跳
Then scream your gills out and flop like a fish
胆小鬼海绵宝宝
SpongeBob Scaredy-Pants